<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Learning Cyber Security</title><link href="https://mikaayenson.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://mikaayenson.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://mikaayenson.github.io/</id><updated>2017-12-02T14:54:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>NIST Dependencies of Other Frameworks</title><link href="https://mikaayenson.github.io/raf_nist_on_frameworks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-02T14:54:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Mika Ayenson</name></author><id>tag:mikaayenson.github.io,2017-12-02:/raf_nist_on_frameworks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Understanding NIST dependancies and why we shouldn't use just one framework.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Why Not Only Use NIST?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Al-Ahmad and Mohammad, no single security framework addresses information security risks adequately.  Organizations face challenges that hinder their risk analysis and try to adopt the best security practices of different frameworks in their assessments.  Similar to NIST, all other frameworks have their strengths and weaknesses in the major functions to identify, protect, detect, respond, and recover.  In the major function to identify within an organization, risk analysis and risk management strategies have several subcategories that NIST does not address solely.  The NIST frame depends on other standards and frameworks like COBIT 5, ISO 27001, and ISA 62440 to provide information in sub-categories like identifying asset vulnerabilities, identifying threats, establishing risk management processes, determining risk tolerance, identifying business impacts, and several others.  When NIST is limited in scope, other frameworks like COBIT and ITIL are preferred since they are more general in nature.  The purpose of the NIST framework was to provide the minimum level of information security requirements for government agencies (Schroeder, n.d.).  The major strength of the framework is that it has a robust catalog of documentation and has a solid foundation since it has been developed over time as technology has progressed.  That major weakness is that the framework doesn’t provide a lot of financial information in the NIST documents.  Organizations choose NIST when an in-depth understanding of controls is necessary and if the organization needs to comply with any US Government regulations.  This focus leaves gaps in the framework for other frameworks like ISO 27002, COBIT, or ITIL to fill.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: &lt;a href="../pages/raf_references.html"&gt;References&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="RAF"></category><category term="cyber"></category></entry><entry><title>NIST Risk Analysis Framework on Webservers</title><link href="https://mikaayenson.github.io/raf_nist_on_webservers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-02T14:54:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Mika Ayenson</name></author><id>tag:mikaayenson.github.io,2017-12-02:/raf_nist_on_webservers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Understanding actionable guidance provided by NIST documentation.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;NIST Risk Analysis Framework on Web Servers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Institute of Standards and Technology has provided specific guidelines on securing web servers.  NIST 800-44 was designed as a framework for, “federal departments and agencies, state agencies, and commercial organizations in installing, configuring, and maintaining secure public Web servers.  It presents generic security principles and covers details specific to the various components of Web content, Web applications, and Web servers (Tracy, Jansen &amp;amp; LcLarnon, 2017).” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The framework recommended mitigation strategies on web server attacks consist of a large checklist provided by NIST 800-44 Appendix E. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;NIST Actionable Web Server Attack Mitigation Guidelines&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt Text" class="img-responsive" height="75%" src="https://mikaayenson.github.io/images/web_server1.jpg" width="75%"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="Alt Text" class="img-responsive" height="75%" src="https://mikaayenson.github.io/images/web_server2.jpg" width="75%"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="Alt Text" class="img-responsive" height="75%" src="https://mikaayenson.github.io/images/web_server3.jpg" width="75%"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="Alt Text" class="img-responsive" height="75%" src="https://mikaayenson.github.io/images/web_server4.jpg" width="75%"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="Alt Text" class="img-responsive" height="75%" src="https://mikaayenson.github.io/images/web_server5.jpg" width="75%"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="Alt Text" class="img-responsive" height="75%" src="https://mikaayenson.github.io/images/web_server6.jpg" width="75%"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="Alt Text" class="img-responsive" height="75%" src="https://mikaayenson.github.io/images/web_server7.jpg" width="75%"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="Alt Text" class="img-responsive" height="75%" src="https://mikaayenson.github.io/images/web_server8.jpg" width="75%"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="Alt Text" class="img-responsive" height="75%" src="https://mikaayenson.github.io/images/web_server9.jpg" width="75%"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tracy, M., Jansen, W., &amp;amp; LcLarnon, M. (2017). Guidelines on Securing Public Web Servers. Gaithersburg: National Institute of Standards and Technology.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: &lt;a href="../pages/raf_references.html"&gt;References&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="RAF"></category><category term="webserver"></category><category term="cyber"></category></entry><entry><title>Risk Analysis Framework Overview</title><link href="https://mikaayenson.github.io/raf_overview.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-02T14:54:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Mika Ayenson</name></author><id>tag:mikaayenson.github.io,2017-12-02:/raf_overview.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Overview of risk management and risk analysis frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Overview of Risk Management and Types of Risks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Risk management is the process of identifying and mitigating threats and risks within an organization.  By understanding these risks, an organization can better protect their assets and minimize financial loss.  In general, there are strategic risks, compliance risks, operational risks, financial risks, and reputational risks that can negatively affect a business (Blackman, 2014).  Every successful organization has a strategic business plan that at times must change due to circumstances.  The changes and effects of that plan leave opportunity for risks.  Risks could negatively affect the strategic goals of the organization like establishing business partnerships, institutional standing, institutional culture of compliance, and advancement strategy.  Organizations need to ensure that they are complying with all laws and regulations.  Things within an organization and laws change.  Not understanding the different compliances as the organization changes leave opportunity for compliance risks.  Examples of compliance risks include contractual agreements with leases or sponsors, regulatory and statutory compliance, industry standards, research grants and contracts, and certifications.  Organizations have to handle their daily processes that achieve business goals.  When those daily tasks fail, it leaves opportunities for operational risks.  Operational risks include computing systems, data security, data management, personnel or even safety.  When organizations have to manage money, there is a possibility of a financial loss and other risks.  Financial risks include penalties and sanctions, loss of revenue, or lawsuits and other damages.  Finally, reputational risks include being labels as an organization that fails to manage effectively compliance, financial operations, or strategic risks.  It could impact the reputation and public image with investors and other customers ("Potential Areas of Risk | Finance", 2017).  Fortunately, there are different risk management frameworks that can be applied to the work environment and help identify, analyze, assess, mitigate, and monitor risks.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: &lt;a href="../pages/raf_references.html"&gt;References&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="RAF"></category><category term="risk assessment framework"></category><category term="cyber"></category></entry><entry><title>Web Server Attacks</title><link href="https://mikaayenson.github.io/web_attacks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-02T14:54:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Mika Ayenson</name></author><id>tag:mikaayenson.github.io,2017-12-02:/web_attacks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Understanding the different types of attacks seen on webservers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Cyber-Attacks on Web Servers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the design of web servers and implementation of the TCP/IP protocol, webservers have vulnerabilities like issues in verification of input data, URL parameter modifications, and session identifier authentication. These types of vulnerabilities lead to numerous attack vectors that traditional network security has a difficult time preventing. For example, there are URL interpretation attacks, SQL Injection attacks, input validation attacks, buffer overflow attacks, impersonation attacks, password-based attacks, denial-of-service attacks, brute force attacks, source code disclosure attacks, cross site scripting attacks, and session hijacking attacks (Mohammad, 2016). Here are five common attacks explained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SQL Injection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a well-known attack that attempts to modify parameters in the URL to directly interact with the backend database. Unauthorized users can input query-like data into the URL that is later interpreted by the database and used to bypass typical security. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Input Validation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adversaries use this type of attack to execute code injected on the webserver. If there is no input validation, users can upload code to the server and then used to retrieve unauthorized information or cause damage to the server. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Source Code Disclosure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adversaries at times want to obtain source code of another organization. Once the source code is obtained, it is then reverse engineered to find other vulnerabilities in the website. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;URL Interpretation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This attack is typically called URL poisoning that affects CGI-based websites. Attackers change the semantics of the URL but keep the syntax to that the request is well-formed legitimate URL. This type of attack allows adversaries to gain information that they typically would not have access to. An example of this would be if an adversary changed the URL that contains account information to another users account ID to load their information using their own approved session token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Denial of Service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A denial of service (DoS) attack is an attack that prevents legitimate users from interacting with the website by flooding the server with too much data to process in a timely manner. At times DoS attacks can crash the server and cause serious damage to the applications running on the webserver. This type of attack is intentionally used to disrupt and damage services of an organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: &lt;a href="../pages/raf_references.html"&gt;References&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="web"></category><category term="webserver"></category><category term="cyber"></category></entry><entry><title>Web Server Functionality</title><link href="https://mikaayenson.github.io/web_functions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-02T14:54:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Mika Ayenson</name></author><id>tag:mikaayenson.github.io,2017-12-02:/web_functions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Understanding what what servers are used for and their core functions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Web Servers and Functionality.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many organizations have web servers in their organization which provides services and information that customers and internal use on a daily basis.  Mozilla’s developer guide has a great explanation of web servers and their functionality.  Web servers have hardware and software that work together to serve web pages.  In general, web servers store components to a website like Office documents, programs, HTML documents, CSS stylesheets, and JavaScript files.  These files are served to the client by a software web server application that handles how URL’s are interpreted from a browser request.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1)    When a user inputs a web address into the browser, the client application divides the URL into the address, path of the content to be retrieved, and protocol. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2)    If a domain name is supplied in the URL, DNS translates the name into an IP address that represents the actual address of the website. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3)    The browser then uses the protocol supplied in the URL to communicate with the web server. For example, it could be HTTP, HTTPS, or FTP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4)    The web server then uses the request type to send data to the web server or get data from the server. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5)   For example, if the request type was a GET request, the browser then must convert the retrieved data into HTML that can be presented in the browser and viewed by the user. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, the communication between a client’s browser is the form of requests and responses. See Mozilla’s developer guide for a deep dive on web servers (Duarte, Mills, Patonnier, Pfeiffer &amp;amp; Culloca, 2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt Text" class="img-responsive" height="75%" src="https://mikaayenson.github.io/images/web_server10.jpg" width="75%"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Duarte, H., Mills, C., Patonnier, J., Pfeiffer, A., &amp;amp; Culloca, F. (2017). What is a web server?. Mozilla Developer Network. Retrieved 2 December 2017, from https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/Common_questions/What_is_a_web_server&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: &lt;a href="../pages/raf_references.html"&gt;References&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="web"></category><category term="webserver"></category><category term="cyber"></category></entry><entry><title>Email Cyber Crime</title><link href="https://mikaayenson.github.io/email_cyber_crime_explained.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-11-14T19:54:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Mika Ayenson</name></author><id>tag:mikaayenson.github.io,2017-11-14:/email_cyber_crime_explained.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Let's do a deep dive into e-mail and cyber crimes.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt Text" class="img-responsive" src="https://mikaayenson.github.io/images/red_email.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E-mail in day-to-day business is an essential capability that empowers employees to communicate internally and externally.  Users receive updates, share documents, receive alerts, organize meetings, share information, and many other things without having to physically meet or call people they want to communicate with.  When e-mails are received, there is a level of trust that the sender is who the mail server says they are.  This trust factor and other technical aspects of mail servers are unfortunately exploited and give adversaries different attack vectors.  In this blog, the client and server fundamentals, examples of e-mail crime committed, vulnerabilities associated with emails, spoofing, tools used to investigate e-mail cybercrime, and laws to fight email cybercrime are discussed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Server and Client Involved in Email Communication&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mail server and endpoint client are the two main nodes used in email communication.  The mail server sends e-mails between endpoints and other mail servers, receives e-mails from endpoints, and stores e-mails for user endpoints.  Mail servers and user endpoints are configured to use the same protocol whether it is POP3, IMAP, SMTP, or HTTP ("Setting Up Mail Servers in Outlook Express", 2017).  The client machines typically send, receive, and store e-mails on endpoints like mobile devices and computers.  From endpoint to endpoint, e-mail must connect to at least one mail server.  Users can use software like Microsoft outlook to send the e-mail, the e-mail is sent to a Microsoft Exchange server, and then ends ultimately at another users e-mail.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Four Examples of Crime Committed by Sending E-mails&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By sending malicious e-mails perpetrators can commit crimes in multiple ways.  Four examples of e-mail crimes are e-mail bombing, e-mails involving threating extortion, e-mail fraud, and maliciously spreading malware.  According to US-CERT, e-mail bombing is when an individual repeatedly sends e-mails targeted at a victim with typically a large and meaningless amount of data ("Email Bombing Spamming", 2017).  The goal of the adversary is to consume a large amount of the victim’s data and network resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example is when computer criminals send threatening e-mails to victims in attempt to extort them.  According to the FBI in 2007, life-threatening e-mails started to trend online that attempted to scare victims into paying thousands on dollars (Online Extortion, 2007).  Although the Internet Crime Complaint Center didn’t report and financial loss for the victims, the act of sending malicious e-mails itself was still a crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spreading malware through e-mails is also a computer crime ("Report Phishing Sites", 2017).  Typically this is sent as a phishing attempt where the adversary tries to trick the victim into opening a file or downloaded and executing a windows binary.  The adversary typically claims that the file is an urgent update and must be executed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, in 2016 the IRS reported e-mail being used fraudulently to send e-mails claiming they were apart of the IRS team so that users would send their personal information (IRS News Releases, 2016).  This was not exactly a spoofing attempt but a few characteristics were similar.  For example, the perpetrator included images that resembled the IRS logos, and posed as the IRS by saying “Your eServices Team” in the from header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a safe precaution, if any e-mails appear suspicious, users can analyze the e-mails headers to verify the e-mails authenticity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Common E-mail Headers and Description Table&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table class="table table-hover table-striped"&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Header Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Protocol&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message date and time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;From&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mailbox of message author&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sender&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mailbox of message sender&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Reply-To&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mailbox for replies to message&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;To&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Primary recipient mailbox&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Carbon-copy recipient mailbox&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bcc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Blind-carbon-copy recipient mailbox&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message-ID&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message identifier&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;In-Reply-To&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Identify replied-to message(s)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;References&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Related message identifier(s)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Subject&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Topic of message&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Comments&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Additional comments about the message&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Keywords&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message key words and/or phrases&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Resent-Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Date and time message is resent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Resent-From&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mailbox of person for whom message is resent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Resent-Sender&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mailbox of person who actually resends the message&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Resent-To&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mailbox to which message is resent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Resent-Cc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mailbox(es) to which message is cc'ed on resend&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Resent-Bcc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mailbox(es) to which message is bcc'ed on resend&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Resent-Reply-To&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Resent reply-to&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Resent-Message-ID&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message identifier for resent message&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Return-Path&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message return path&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Received&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mail transfer trace information&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Encrypted&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message encryption information&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Disposition-Notification-To&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mailbox for sending disposition notification&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Disposition-Notification-Options&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Disposition notification options&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Accept-Language&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Language(s) for auto-responses&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Original-Message-ID&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Original message identifier&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PICS-Label&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PICS rating label&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Encoding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message encoding and other information&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;List-Archive&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;URL of mailing list archive&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;List-Help&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;URL for mailing list information&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;List-ID&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mailing list identifier&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;List-Owner&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;URL for mailing list owner's mailbox&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;List-Post&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;URL for mailing list posting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;List-Subscribe&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;URL for mailing list subscription&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;List-Unsubscribe&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;URL for mailing list unsubscription&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message-Context&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Type or context of message&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DL-Expansion-History&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Trace of distribution lists passed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alternate-Recipient&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Controls forwarding to alternate recipients&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Original-Encoded-Information-Types&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Body part types in message&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Content-Return&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Return content on non-delivery?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Generate-Delivery-Report&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Request delivery report generation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Prevent-NonDelivery-Report&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Non-delivery report required?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Obsoletes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Reference message to be replaced&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Supersedes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Reference message to be replaced&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Content-Identifier&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message content identifier&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Delivery-Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message delivery time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Expiry-Date&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message expiry time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Expires&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message expiry time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Reply-By&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Time by which a reply is requested&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Importance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message importance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Incomplete-Copy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Body parts are missing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Priority&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message priority&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sensitivity&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message content sensitivity&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Language&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X.400 message content language&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Conversion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Conversion allowed?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Conversion-With-Loss&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lossy conversion allowed?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message-Type&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message type: delivery report?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Autosubmitted&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Automatically submitted indicator&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Autoforwarded&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Automatically forwarded indicator&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Discarded-X400-IPMS-Extensions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X.400 IPM extensions discarded&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Discarded-X400-MTS-Extensions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X.400 MTS extensions discarded&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Disclose-Recipients&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Disclose names of other recipients?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deferred-Delivery&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deferred delivery information&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Latest-Delivery-Time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Latest delivery time requested&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Originator-Return-Address&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Originator return address&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X400-Content-Identifier&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Message content identifier&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X400-Content-Return&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Return content on non-delivery?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X400-Content-Type&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X400 content type&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X400-MTS-Identifier&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X400 MTS-Identifier&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X400-Originator&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X400 Originator&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X400-Received&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X400 Received&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X400-Recipients&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X400 Recipients&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X400-Trace&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X400 Trace&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Four Examples of Crimes Supported by E-mails&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several different e-mail crimes that are supported through e-mails like harassment, blackmailing, identity fraud, and even sharing classified information.  When people send threatening e-mails they are cyber bullying.  Similar to bullying in general, when people bully victims through e-mail, they are breaking cyber harassment laws.  Similarly, blackmail through e-mail is another supported crime.  Blackmail just like harassment is when individuals direct threating or abusive messages to another individual.  Blackmail extends the crime by extorting the victim.  Identity fraud is a supported by e-mails by being apart of the attack strategy.  Criminals send e-mails either to individuals or businesses posing as another person to steal personal data or defraud another individual.  An example of this is when a person sends an e-mail to a bank posing as another individual to gain access to their bank account.  Finally, something as egregious espionage is supported through e-mail.  For example, if an individual’s sends classified documents from the secret internet protocol router network to the non-classified internet protocol router network, they are committing a cyber crime.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;E-mail Spoofing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example of crime supported by e-mails that are committed by sending an e-mail is called e-mail spoofing.  Adversaries sometimes use simple tactics to spoof e-mails and sometimes simply just say that they are someone in the e-mail that they really are not.  E-mail spoofing is not the same thing as forging, where an individual sends an e-mail with header information that appears to originate from a source that is not the actually source.  E-mail addresses can be spoofed, the content of the e-mail can be faked, and the headers can be forged ("Spoofed/Forged Email", 2017).  Each tactic is used to trick the user into revealing sensitive information to the attacker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Common Invesigative E-mail Cybercrime Tools Table&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than looking at header information directly, there are several tools that help investigators in e-mail cybercrime like eMailTrackerPro, EmailTracer, Adcomplain, Aid4Mail Forensic, AbusePipe, AccessData’s FTK, EnCase Forensic, FINALeMAIL, Forensics Investigation Toolkit (FIT), and Paraben (Network) E-mail Examiner (Tariq Banday, 2011).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="table table-hover table-striped"&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Tool&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;eMailTrackerPro&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Analyses e-mail headers to identify the senders IP address.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;EmailTracer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Indian law enforcement tool to trace IP address and e-mail headers of originator.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adcomplain&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tool to report inappropriate commercial e-mails in postings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aid4Mail&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forensic    E-mail forensic tool to e-discovery and litigation support.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AbusePipe&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tool to analyze complaint e-mails to determine e-mail originator.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AccessData’s FTK&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Court-validated digital forensic investigator with e-mail capabilities.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;EnCase Forensic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Digital forensics tool with imaging capabilities.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FINALeMAIL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;E-mail recovery tool.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Forensics&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Investigation Toolkit (FIT)    Packet capturing tool to ingest raw data and use in fraud and forensic law enforcement.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Paraben (Network)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;E-mail Examiner Tool to search through e-mail applications, recover e-mails and analyze e-mails.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Two US laws Fighting Against E-mail Cybercrime&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two laws that help the United States fight against e-mail cyber are the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 (CFAA), and the Identity Theft Enforcement and Restitution Act of 2008 (ITERA).  ITERA was created to increase federal prosecution for identity theft related crimes and help the victims by providing restitution for the victims ("H.R.4718 - 99th Congress (1985-1986): Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986", 2017).  CFAA was created to persecute criminals that intentionally committed computer fraud ("Identity Theft Enforcement and Restitution Act of 2007 (2007 - S.  2168)", 2017).  Although ITERA applies to identity theft in general, both of these laws also apply to cybercrimes including e-mail related crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When e-mail capabilities are used in an organization, there are several different components to consider when trying protecting a business from adversaries.  There is the server and client that must be created and properly configured, different threat vectors that adversaries can use to attack individuals, tools and techniques used to investigate e-mail related crimes, and finally laws that are designed to protect against e-mail related computer crimes.  Each of these areas has to be properly assessed to mitigate cyber crimes within the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email Bombing Spamming. (2017). Cert.org. Retrieved 14 November 2017, from https://www.cert.org/historical/tech_tips/email_bombing_spamming.cfm?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H.R.4718 - 99th Congress (1985-1986): Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986. (2017). Congress.gov. Retrieved 14 November 2017, from https://www.congress.gov/bill/99th-congress/house-bill/4718&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identity Theft Enforcement and Restitution Act of 2007 (2007 - S. 2168). (2017). GovTrack.us. Retrieved 14 November 2017, from https://www.govtrack.us/congress/bills/110/s2168&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IRS News Releases. (2016). IRS Warns Tax Professionals of New e-Services Email Scam. Retrieved from https://www.irs.gov/newsroom/irs-warns-tax-professionals-of-new-eservices-email-scam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online Extortion. (2007). E-Mail Scam Includes Hit-Man Threat. Retrieved from https://archives.fbi.gov/archives/news/stories/2007/january/threatscam_111507&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Report Phishing Sites. (2017). United States Computer Emergency Readiness Team. Retrieved 13 November 2017, from https://www.us-cert.gov/report-phishing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting Up Mail Servers in Outlook Express. (2017). Support.microsoft.com. Retrieved 14 November 2017, from https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/2419526/setting-up-mail-servers-in-outlook-express&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoofed/Forged Email. (2017). Cert.org. Retrieved 13 November 2017, from https://www.cert.org/historical/tech_tips/email_spoofing.cfm?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tariq Banday, M. (2011). Techniques and Tools for Forensic Investigation of E-mail. International Journal Of Network Security &amp;amp; Its Applications, 3(6), 227-241. http://dx.doi.org/10.5121/ijnsa.2011.3617&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
var tables, i;
tables = document.getElementsByTagName('table');
for (i=0;i&lt;tables.length;i++) {
  tables[i].className = 'table table-bordered table-hover';
  tables[i].border = 1;
}
&lt;/script&gt;</content><category term="email"></category><category term="cyber"></category><category term="cybercrime"></category><category term="computer crime"></category></entry></feed>